# zhenwu@cs.stonybrook.edu thtps://zhengyuwu.me

# Zhengyu Wu



# ABOUT ME

I am a second-year Computer Science Ph.D Student at Stony Brook University. I work in the NetSys Lab with my advisor, Aruna Balasubramanian. My research interests include network performance, mainly peer-to-peer networks and decentralized distributed storage systems.

## **EDUCATION**

Ph.D Student in Computer Science

Stony Brook University, New York, USA

Jan **2022 - Present** GPA: 3.93/4.0

Advisor: Prof. Aruna Balasubramanian

**B.S.** Computer Science

Stony Brook University, New York, USA

Aug 2017 - May 2021

# **PUBLICATION**

# Is IPFS Ready for Decentralized Video Streaming?

ChengHao Ryan Yang, Zhengyu Wu, Santiago Vargas, and Aruna Balasubramanian.

WWW2023

GPA: 3.80/4.0

• The video playback experience on IPFS suffers from network instability and static video quality. Traditional ABR streaming performs poorly due to inaccurate network estimation. The proposed IPFS-aware algorithm, called Telescope, can update ABR's estimation on the fly and significantly improve the video playback experience.

#### Sensitive Files on IPFS?

Under Submission

• IPFS is a public decentralized storage system that is content-addressing based, which makes it easy to inadvertently share private files on the platform. This poses a risk as IPFS can store files for extended periods. Our investigation revealed the presence of sensitive files like SSH keys and API keys on IPFS, highlighting the potential risks of accidental file sharing.

#### Work Experience

#### Graduate Teaching Assistant

Fall 2021 - Fall 2022

New York

Stony Brook University

- ullet Graduate teaching assistant for Introduction to Network Administration. Introduced students with hands-on experience on fundamentals of network management, such as TCP/IP networking protocols, hardware, architecture, media, and software
- Graduate teaching assistant for Computer Networks. Helped students learn the fundamental structure of the Internet.

# Web/Database Support

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Stony Brook University

New York

• Maintained the Computer Science Department's websites at Stony Brook University by using Drupal, a widely used content management system (CMS), and MySQL.

# Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Spring 2019, Fall 2019

Stony Brook University

New York

- Undergraduate teaching assistant for Computer Science I. Helped students learn the fundamentals of objective programming.
- Undergraduate teaching assistant for Fundamentals of Software Development. Introduced students to systematic design, development and testing of software systems.

Founder
Hoshiro Entertainment

Jun 2018 - Present

New York

- Founded a company services translating games from Japanese to English and Chinese.
- Successfully maintained a group of over 10 translators and helped partners reach over a million dollar in sales.

#### AWARDS & HONORS

Stony Brook University Scholars (2017 - 2021) IMC Travel Grant (2022) GAANN Fellowship (2023) Stony Brook University Provost Scholarship (2017 - 2021)